Hi guys, in this video we will
talk about the business updates of three companies.
All three are from the financial sector.  The first
one is SG Fins.  After that insurance is
ICICI LBR General Insurance and the third one
is HDB Financial Services.  So their
business updates have come for Q4 FY 26.  So
let us start one by one starting off
with SD Finserv.  So if you
see the loan book growth of SG Fisf, it is around 96%,
stipends growth right around 96%, their
loan book growth has been around Q4 FY26, their current
loan book size is
around Rs 3900 crore, the surprising
thing is that the NPA of this company, the
NPA of the financier is nil.
What does this company basically do?
What is their business?  They get to know.  It basically does
supply chain financing.  If I
try to explain it to you in layman terms.  Now a bigger company than Lets
is T Motors.  Now Tata Motors has dealer
distributors through whom Tata
Motors sells its goods.
Now suppose the dealer distributor does
not have the money to buy the goods from Tata Motors.
That is where companies like SG Finserv
step in.  She says that we will
give you the money.  You purchase the goods.
We will finance your tax invoice.  That is their
basic business.  This is how they do their
business.  Now the best thing is that the
reason for NPA being zero is that
what do they say about you?  All these industry majors are
called industry majors.  These
big companies like Tata Motors
or your Apollo Tyres,
Polycab.  What do all these companies, or
any other infrastructure related
companies like steel etc., do?
Suppose if these dealer distributors
default, then these people
tie up with them in such a way that they will stop
supplying the goods to SD Finerf from next time.
So what happens because of this is
that the scope of default here is
next to nil.  That is why if you
see their NPA figures, it is nil.
If I talk about other figures, then their
ROE which is return on assets which is
quite healthy is around 4.8%.
ROE is around 12%.  This means that this
company still has a lot of scope for leverage.
What is our return on equity, that is,
if you multiply return on assets by leverage
you get the ROE.  So
this company still has a lot of scope for leverage here.
If I
talk about NPA, then as I said,
their NPA is zero.  Now you think, I was
looking at the same thing, in the PowerPoint presentation, the
reason for their stipend and magnificent growth is that from where
they have financed it.
Finance has been given to that dealer distributor of that industry where there is a huge
tail wind of the industry.
First of all, Auto and Auto Entireties, if
Mahindra & Mahindra becomes Tata Motors or
Fords Motors, just to name a few,
then how has the entire
auto segment grown so much here.
When an industry or a sector
grows, its dealer
distributor also has to
bring the goods as quickly as possible, empty them,
restock them, so for that,
money is required for working capital to
stock up the inventory, to pile it up.
So that's where the growth is.  That is
growth in the sector itself.  That is why they have so
much growth.  Then
he has financed auto ancillaries.  Autos
became auto incivilities.  He has financed in the power sector.
All the infrastructure related companies like
your steel tubes and pipes, then your
wires and cables like Polycab KEI,
they have also financed some hospitals.
So overall you will see that the
reason for their growth is that they have
financed those dealer distributors
who come from the industry where tremendous
tailwinds have been seen in the last one and a half years.
If I talk about their guidance for FY27 next year,
they have said that they will
increase their AUM by around 25 to 30%.  Pad growth will be
around 30%.  This will increase the return on equity to
around 14-15%.
This is what the company believes.  So keep
tracking this company.  The model of the company is
quite good.  The best thing is that
they have zero NPA till now.  Bad loans have
n't even happened yet.  Whatever he has sent has come back to
him.
No loan has gone bad yet.  So
it's a very interesting company to watch out
for in the coming future.  Right?  And if the growth continues in this manner.
Basically you have to
see whether NPA comes up in future or
not.  And if NPA comes then it will be difficult.
If NP does not come from this level,
if the growth continues at the same level or let's say around 25 to
30%, then it is talking about increasing its AOM growth.
Right moving on to the
next company which is the ICICI LBRD
General Insurance.  ICICI LBRD General
Insurance
is the largest private insurer in its segment.  of General Insurance.
Their market share has increased by around 200 basis points in the last two-three
years.  It has increased from around
8% to around 10.7%.
Now 2% in 3 years does
n't sound like a lot.  But private
insurance and general insurance are
still very fragmented markets.   There
is a lot of competition in this.  There
is intense competition.  It is also from the public insurers.  It is
also available from private insurers.
If we talk about their results, what is
their GDPI result
?  Gross Direct Premium Income.  So
their premium income has
increased by around 189%.  If you talk about the growth of their PAT, it has
increased by around 15-16%.
Now insurance business is a bit
complicated business.  Because
look, you the customer pays you a premium.
You charge a premium upfront from the customer.
After that, when the claim comes, the claim has to be settled.
So this is the ratio of
how much premium will be collected and how much claim we will have to
settle.  There is a field
called actuarial science.  From there,
after applying it, a company
is able to estimate how much our premium will be and
how much we will have to settle in the claim.
Here a ratio comes into play which is
called the combined ratio.  Now the
combined ratio for an insurance
tells how much premiums have been collected
and how much claims have we paid from that premium
and what is the remaining expenses incurred in running the business.
So basically
if you talk about ICICI LBD,
its combined ratio is around 1112%.  Now if
you say that their premiums are low.
Their claims and other business running
expenses are high, so how does the company survive
?  So the company survives in the same way
that the claims, the premium which it
takes upfront and collects from the customer, it does
not keep it in cash, it
invests it also, so the
return generated from the investment is basically their
income, so you will see that for
most of the insurers it is above 100%, which is the
combined ratio,
if it goes above 115, it is a bit of an
alarming bell, it means that there will be difficulty
in profitability in your underwriting,
then you will have problem in surviving.
If it is around 11012, it
means it will work.  He is fine.
If we talk about ICICI LBA General Insurance, then
their health insurance
segment is growing very fast.  I
think it has grown around 38 to 40%
year on year.  So you will
see that obviously because
people are more aware about health insurance and
after Covid, people have become more aware about
their health in health insurance
and any
fresher who joins a job,
nowadays the first thing he looks for is to take a term
insurance and a health insurance
so that whatever I save in future, say
in 5 years, 7 years, 10 years, it does
not happen that it gets
completely spent in the form of hospital expenses, that is why
what happens by taking an insurance is that even
if you get some disease, the
insurance company takes care of that thing.
So basically this is all there is.
I told you about the combined ratio.
I spoke about market share.
If you look at the company now, its growth has been
around 12, 14, 15% in the last 3 years.  There has
not been much growth beyond that.  The most important thing is increase
in market share.  Market share has improved by 2%.
And basically, right now the
market capitalization of this company ICICI LBD is around Rs 90,000 crore.
This means a well established company
and right now you are getting it around 30 PE with
trailing PE.  If we assume that
in the coming time, there is a slight increase in growth,
it can grow at around 20%, then
this company
may do well in the coming time and the market
can reward this company accordingly.
Moving on to the next company
which is the
HDB Financial Services, if you
talk about the growth of their gross loan book, then
their growth has been around 10.91%.   If
you talk about disbursement,
their disbursement growth has been around 13%.   The
most important thing is the Nim.  There has been a
lot of increase in the minimum.  This time
their loss has been 8.43% points.  Its net interest margin, which was
around 7.55% in Q4 FY25 to Q4 FY25 last year, has
increased to around 8.23 ​​percentage
points.  There has also been improvement in the cost to income
ratio.  This
time it was 39.5%.  If we talk about Q4 FY25 last year, it
was around 42.8% to 42.9%, it has improved to 39.5%.   There is a
problem, the credit cost has
increased a bit and GS3 which is the gross
stage three loans.  This means that
there has been a slight increase in the bad loans and credit costs.  So now we will have to
look at that company.
Who calls the company management and
what does it tell after that, why has it
increased, that will have to be seen, it is almost certain
because the growth of the economy has been a
bit sluggish, a little
struggle has been seen and the way there
are geopolitical tensions or the
rising input costs, all this can happen.
These are likely reasons.  Right now we are only
able to guess and speculate
until the management
comes and speaks clearly.  Rest, if you
talk about their ROE,
their ROE is around 50% of 2.50.
It is currently generating ROE of around 1415%.
So you can say that
this leverage is around five times 5 and a half times.  It is
not that much.  It is not that
less.  It's all right.  So This Is All About
The Three Companies Guys.
About the three companies from the financial sector.   The
First One Was SG Finser.  The result has been very good.  The
company
needs to be tracked.  After that ICICI LB General
Insurance not that great result but the
most important thing is increase in market
share.  If there is even a little bit of good growth from here, the
market can reward it well.
Then if you
talk about HDB Financial Service, then HDB
Financial Service has also got OKOK result.
However, there has been a slight increase in bad loans.
But the good part is the
stock is
not that expensive right now anyway.  If there is a little more
growth in the future.  Suppose the loan book
or the disbursement, it can be
around 18, 17, 18%.  So
if you look at it on a forward basis, right now
its price to book trades around 2.6.  In the
times to come,
if the growth increases a little, then this company will become
worth watching.  So this is all about these
three companies.  I hope you guys like the
videos.  If you liked it then definitely
like it.  Share it with your friends.
If you have any comments or questions,
please post them.  I would love to
answer all of them.  See you in the next video
with another company update.  Till then,
thank you so much and bye.